<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>geek girl codes</title>
    <description>A super rad girl dev blog.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>2018-09-15</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 23:10:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Zine Culture + Computer Science</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am not a book reader. It is difficult for me to sit down and just get ‘absorbed’ in a book. However, with comics? It’s different. Comics are dynamic, graphic, and play out like a film. The same goes with zine’s. They are colorful, unique, filled with tid bits of information displayed in fun ways. There are zine’s for pretty much any subject you can imagine, this includes computer science! I wanted to share some unique comics/zine’s that exist on the web that are out to teach cool things about programming and computers with a more visual twist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;julia-evans&quot;&gt;Julia Evans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i66.tinypic.com/wjh1md.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
This girl has an amazing mission statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m trying to create a small corner of the internet which is never condescending or rude or dismissive and where I just talk about learning hard things and doing hard things in a practical and friendly way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia experiments with alternative ways to teach hard concepts through making zines. She is a badass software developer from Montreal and she focuses on deeply understanding the underlying systems essential to do technically innovative work. Some of the zine’s she wrote include: Profiling &amp;amp; Tracing with Perf, Let’s Learn tcpdump!, and Linux Debugging Tools You’ll Love. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jvns.ca/zines/&quot;&gt;Be sure to check out her website and view all of her amazing work!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bubblesort-zines&quot;&gt;BubbleSort Zines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i68.tinypic.com/2lxxg28.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amy is an alumni of MIT and created this project out of a dream of hers to create a series of zines that cover computer science concepts in an accessible way. She left her job at Airbnb after a successful Kickstarter compaign and BubbleSort Zines was born! Amy’s goal is to frame computer science fundamentals in a way that is much more accessable to those who may not think they have a place in the subject. It is about improving diversity and reaching underrepresented demographics. It is less about getting young girls interested in math and science and more about making them feel welcome, included, and supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is so relatable for me. My first experience with programming was on the web back when I was in middle school but I never thought that it was an actual career path. I fell behind in math and science subjects and was never encouraged to try harder. It wasn’t until later in life that I realized I love math and science! More importantly, I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; programming! Framing technical subjects in a way that is more appealing can help encourage younger girls to stick with it. Math? It’s hard! Programming? It’s hard! But that is what makes it so rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support Amy’s initiative and also get some rad t-shirts, &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.bubblesort.io/collections/all&quot;&gt;check out her website and buy everything!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;glitch-you-got-this&quot;&gt;Glitch You Got This!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i68.tinypic.com/4kis11.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t already familiar with &lt;a href=&quot;https://glitch.com/&quot;&gt;Glitch&lt;/a&gt;, I highly recommend checking them out. It is a friendly community where anyone can create an app or website instantly. Their web IDE compiles and updates everything as you type and can even allow you to code with your friends! It is brought to you by the same team that create Slack. This same group created a couple of really cool zines that focus on web app technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You Got This! has two parts: the first is &lt;a href=&quot;https://glitch.com/you-got-this&quot;&gt;how to make web apps with Node.js&lt;/a&gt;, the second is &lt;a href=&quot;https://glitch.com/you-got-this/2&quot;&gt;how to make web apps with React.js&lt;/a&gt;. They focus on the key concepts for creating web apps with these frameworks, stories on how developers carved their own paths into coding, tips from experts, and more. They are very nicely illustrated and super colorful. I highly recommend downloading and following along. The best part is you can use Glitch to experiment with these frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>2018-09-15</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/articles/2018-09/zine-culture-and-computer-science</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/articles/2018-09/zine-culture-and-computer-science</guid>
        
        
        <category>cool stuff</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
